Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we're going to be purchasing some wine today, right Marco?
我是Catherine，今天我们打算买些葡萄酒，对吧，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to go to the shop and we're going to try to look for some wine that will
今天我们要去商店，试着找一种葡萄酒，它要能
go well with the type of food that we're having.
和我们吃的食物搭配得很好。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to be learning a lot of specific terms.
所以我们会学到很多专业术语。
This is an advanced lesson.
这是一节高级课程。
So we expect that most of the basics you already know, but some of these more difficult words
我们假设你已经掌握了大部分基础知识，但一些较难的词汇
and phrases are going to be our focus.
和短语将是我们的重点。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
那我们来听听今天的对话吧。
Hello there.
你好。
Welcome to Wine World.
欢迎来到葡萄酒世界。
Let me know if I can help you out at all.
如果需要帮忙，请随时告诉我。
Yes, please.
好的，请。
I could really use some help.
我真的很需要一些帮助。
I'm going over to my boss's house for dinner tonight and I don't know what kind of wine
我今晚要去老板家吃晚饭，不知道应该带什么
I should bring.
酒。
Okay.
好的。
Do you know what kind of food will be served?
你知道会吃什么食物吗？
Well, his wife is Japanese.
嗯，他妻子是日本人。
He said she makes really good sushi.
他说她做的寿司很好吃。
That's a bit of a challenge.
这有点挑战性。
Sushi is notoriously difficult to pair with wine.
寿司是出了名的难与葡萄酒搭配。
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我们看看。
It'll have to be a white wine, of course.
当然得是白葡萄酒。
Why?
为什么？
Wouldn't a red wine go well with sushi?
红葡萄酒不能和寿司搭配吗？
No, I don't think so.
不，我不这么认为。
Sushi is a very delicately flavored food and red wine would be a jarring contrast.
寿司是一种味道非常细腻的食物，红葡萄酒会形成刺眼的对比。
You need a white wine which has more subtle flavors to complement the fish.
你需要一种味道更柔和的白葡萄酒来衬托鱼的味道。
I see.
我明白了。
So I should get a bottle of Chardonnay.
那我应该买一瓶霞多丽。
That's a white wine, right?
那是白葡萄酒，对吧？
Yes, Chardonnay is a white wine, but I'm not sure it'd be your best bet.
是的，霞多丽是白葡萄酒，但我不确定它是最好的选择。
Chardonnay is one of the more full-bodied whites and tends to be a bit oaky.
霞多丽是比较醇厚的白葡萄酒之一，往往带点橡木味。
I'd suggest you go for something brighter like this Sauvignon Blanc from New Zealand.
我建议你选一种更清爽的，比如这款新西兰长相思。
Oh, the Sauvignon Blanc?
哦，长相思？
What's that?
那是什么？
That's another varietal or type of grape, just like Chardonnay.
那是另一种葡萄品种，就像霞多丽一样。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
The label says it's got attractive citrus and grassy aromas that give way to crisp mineral
标签上说它有诱人的柑橘和青草香气，带来清爽的矿物
flavors and a bone-dry finish.
风味和极干的口感。
Serve chilled.
冰镇后饮用。
Oh no, how long will it take to chill the wine?
哦不，冰镇酒要多久？
I'm on my way to dinner now.
我现在就要去吃饭了。
Oh, it's okay, don't worry.
哦，没关系，别担心。
We'll just choose a wine from the cooler.
我们直接从冷藏柜里选一瓶酒。
We don't have quite as extensive a selection over here, but this Rhone Valley White would
这边的选择没那么丰富，但这款罗纳河谷白葡萄酒
be lovely.
会很不错。
All right, what varietal is that?
好的，那是什么品种？
Well, this is a French wine, so they don't always specify the varietal on the label.
嗯，这是法国葡萄酒，所以标签上不一定会标明品种。
The French believe that the soil a grape is grown in is one of the most important factors
法国人认为葡萄生长的土壤是决定葡萄酒最终风味
in the final flavor of the wine.
最重要的因素之一。
This wine is probably a blend of a few different types of grapes, mostly Viognier, I'd guess.
这款酒可能是几种不同葡萄的混合，我猜主要是维欧尼。
And you think this is a good wine?
你觉得这是好酒吗？
Yes, this is one of our best sellers.
是的，这是我们最畅销的酒之一。
It's not quite as dry as the Sauvignon Blanc we were looking at earlier, which means it's
它不像我们之前看的长相思那么干，这意味着它
more approachable.
更容易入口。
It's light and crisp with a bit of a vanilla aroma.
它清淡爽口，带有一点香草香气。
Perfect, I'll take it.
完美，我买了。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So now we're talking about wines, and one of the first things that really pop up is
现在我们谈论葡萄酒，首先提到的是
when we're talking about sushi and how we're trying to get a wine to go well with sushi.
关于寿司，以及我们如何尝试让葡萄酒与寿司搭配。
All right, so the phrase here was to pair with wine.
好的，这里的短语是“与葡萄酒搭配”。
So sushi is notoriously difficult to pair with wine.
所以寿司是出了名的难与葡萄酒搭配。
All right, so when you talk about wine, you talk about pairing it with food, P-A-I-R,
好的，当你谈论葡萄酒时，你会谈论它与食物的搭配，P-A-I-R，
to pair.
搭配。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, if you're having meat or poultry or chicken, you try to pair it with a wine
比如，如果你吃肉或家禽或鸡肉，你会尝试把它与葡萄酒搭配，
so basically that the flavors go well together.
基本上是为了让味道相得益彰。
So commonly we say that red wine pairs well with red meat, or fish and white wine pair
所以我们常说红葡萄酒与红肉搭配得好，或者鱼和白葡萄酒搭配
well together.
得好。
So you're pairing these two things means you're using them in the same meal.
所以搭配这两样东西意味着你在同一餐中使用它们。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So when we're talking about pairing a wine with sushi, the girl said, well, what about
所以当我们谈论葡萄酒与寿司搭配时，女孩说，嗯，那
red wine?
红葡萄酒呢？
Wouldn't that pair well with sushi?
它不能和寿司搭配吗？
And the attendant said, no, the red wine would be a jarring contrast.
服务员说，不行，红葡萄酒会形成一种刺眼的对比。
So first of all, we have this word jarring.
首先，我们来看这个词“jarring”。
Something is jarring if it's loud, shocking, abrasive, difficult, annoying.
“Jarring”指的是刺耳、令人震惊、粗糙、困难、烦人的东西。
So something that's jarring is loud.
所以，“jarring”的东西就是刺耳的。
And a contrast is something that shows the differences in something.
而“contrast”是指显示事物差异的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So when we're saying that it would be a jarring contrast to have sushi with red wine, we're
所以当我们说用寿司配红葡萄酒会形成一种刺眼的对比时，
saying that they're just too different.
意思是它们太不一样了。
Sushi is too different from the red wine flavor, so they wouldn't go well together.
寿司和红葡萄酒的味道差异太大，所以它们搭配不好。
That's right.
没错。
And since jarring means it's a bad thing, we think the flavor will be wrong.
而且因为“jarring”意味着不好的事情，我们认为味道会不对。
It'll be bad.
会很难喝。
So we need to look for something else.
所以我们需要找别的酒。
And the salesperson suggested a wine that has more subtle flavors, white wine.
销售员建议了一种味道更细腻的酒——白葡萄酒。
That's right.
没错。
So this word subtle is actually spelled S-U-B-T-L-E, but the B is silent.
所以这个词“subtle”实际上拼写是S-U-B-T-L-E，但B不发音。
That's right.
没错。
So we say subtle.
所以我们读作“subtle”。
And it's actually great because it's kind of like the opposite of jarring.
这其实很棒，因为它有点像“jarring”的反义词。
Something that's not jarring is subtle.
不刺眼的东西就是细腻的。
Right.
对。
So it's a little bit more, I don't know, like relaxed, like not as loud.
所以它更，怎么说呢，更放松，不那么张扬。
It's not obvious.
它不明显。
You have to really think about it and look for it.
你得仔细想，仔细找。
Something that's subtle is not obvious.
细腻的东西就是不明显的。
That's right.
没错。
And now we're talking about one specific type of white wine.
现在我们讨论一种特定的白葡萄酒。
We have a Chardonnay.
我们有霞多丽。
All right.
好的。
So we know that there are many, many different kinds of wine out there, but there are some
我们知道世界上有很多很多种葡萄酒，但有一些
very common ones.
非常常见的。
And Chardonnay is one of those.
霞多丽就是其中之一。
I think Chardonnay tends to be a bit fruitier.
我觉得霞多丽往往更带果味。
Australia has some famous Chardonnays.
澳大利亚有一些著名的霞多丽。
California has some famous Chardonnays.
加利福尼亚也有一些著名的霞多丽。
Just remember that Chardonnay is a kind of white wine.
记住，霞多丽是一种白葡萄酒。
That's right.
没错。
And one of the ways that they used it to describe Chardonnay is that it's one of the more
他们用来描述霞多丽的一种方式是说它是更
full-bodied whites.
醇厚的白葡萄酒之一。
All right.
好的。
So whites here, we're talking about white wines, but something that's full-bodied.
所以这里的“whites”指的是白葡萄酒，但“full-bodied”是什么意思？
What does that mean, Marco?
这是什么意思，Marco？
So if a wine is full-bodied, it means that it has a little bit of a stronger flavor,
如果一款酒是“full-bodied”，意味着它味道更浓一些，
like it's a more complete flavor.
就像味道更完整。
It's not as subtle.
它不那么细腻。
All right.
好的。
So we know that white wines are a bit more subtle than red wines in this case, but within
所以我们知道在这种情况下白葡萄酒比红葡萄酒更细腻，但在
white wines, you can have one that's very full-bodied.
白葡萄酒中，你可以有非常醇厚的。
So this is a great phrase for describing wine.
所以这是描述葡萄酒的一个很棒的说法。
We don't really talk about other things being full-bodied, but wine can be full-bodied if
我们通常不把其他东西说成“full-bodied”，但葡萄酒可以，如果
it really has what you say, Marco, this big full taste, a bright taste.
它真的有你说的那种，Marco，那种饱满浓郁的味道，明亮的味道。
That's right.
没错。
And actually the sales attendant suggested that, well, since the Chardonnay is too or
实际上，销售员建议说，既然霞多丽太醇厚或
is more full-bodied, then he would recommend maybe a Sauvignon Blanc.
更醇厚，那他可能会推荐长相思。
All right.
好的。
So Sauvignon Blanc.
所以是长相思。
Blanc is the French word for white, but we use this all the time in English.
“Blanc”是法语中“白”的意思，但我们在英语中经常用。
Sauvignon Blanc being the kind of wine.
长相思是一种葡萄酒。
Again, it's a white wine.
同样，它是一种白葡萄酒。
And it's a bit brighter than the Chardonnay.
而且它比霞多丽更清爽一些。
That's what the salesperson said.
销售员是这么说的。
That's right.
没错。
And when we're talking about wines, either red wines or white wines, the way to describe
当我们谈论葡萄酒，无论是红葡萄酒还是白葡萄酒，描述
it or the different varieties is actually a varietal of the wines or the type of grape.
它们或不同品种的方式实际上是葡萄酒的品种或葡萄的类型。
Right.
对。
So varietal.
所以是“varietal”。
So you think of variety, varietal.
你可以联想到“variety”（品种），“varietal”。
Varietal is a specific wine word that we use to describe the kind of grape that go into
“Varietal”是一个特定的葡萄酒词汇，用来描述用于
a wine.
酿造葡萄酒的葡萄种类。
So we know wine generally comes from grapes.
所以我们知道葡萄酒通常来自葡萄。
They're crushed down.
它们被压碎。
And then the alcohol comes from all the sugars.
然后酒精来自所有的糖分。
But each different kind of grape has a different flavor.
但每种不同的葡萄都有不同的味道。
And that's the varietal, the kind of grape.
那就是“varietal”，葡萄的种类。
That's right.
没错。
So just think of it as the variety of the wines that you have.
所以只要把它想成你拥有的葡萄酒的品种。
And it's a word used specifically for wines.
而且这是一个专门用于葡萄酒的词。
And well, when the attendant kept talking about the wines and the types of wines they
当服务员继续谈论那里的葡萄酒和葡萄酒类型时，
have there, he mentioned that they have a small selection in the refrigerator or in
他提到他们在冰箱或
the cooler.
冷却器里有一个小选择。
So selection in this case means what the store has to offer.
所以这里的“选择”指的是商店里有什么可供挑选的。
It means all the wines that they sell.
它指的是他们出售的所有葡萄酒。
So maybe if you have an extensive selection, it means you have many, many, many different
所以如果你有丰富的选择，那就意味着你有很多很多很多不同的
kinds to choose from.
种类可以选。
But if you don't have an extensive selection, you have very few wines, that means that you
但如果你没有丰富的选择，那你只有很少的葡萄酒，这意味着你
have fewer things to sell.
可卖的东西更少。
That's right.
没错。
So a wide selection of wines or a small selection of wines.
所以可以是广泛的葡萄酒选择，或者少量的葡萄酒选择。
And lastly, talking about varietals, we also have what we call a blend, a blend of a few
最后，谈到葡萄品种，我们还有所谓的混酿，即混合几种
different types of grapes.
不同类型的葡萄。
Right.
对。
So you can have blends of different things.
所以你可以有不同东西的混酿。
But in terms of wine, we're talking about using different grapes together to make one
但就葡萄酒而言，我们说的是把不同的葡萄一起用来酿造一种
wine.
酒。
All right.
好的。
So this is something that's pretty common and it's a way to achieve different flavors.
所以这是很常见的事情，也是实现不同风味的一种方式。
That's right.
没错。
So a blend.
所以就是混酿。
You also talk about it in, I think, whiskeys.
我想，在威士忌里也会提到这个。
You have blended whiskeys.
有混合威士忌。
That's right.
没错。
You can have a single malt, which is one grain in one barrel, or you can have a blend, which
你可以有单一麦芽，即一种谷物在一个桶里陈酿，或者有混酿，即
would be different grains fermented in different barrels mixed together later.
不同谷物在不同桶里发酵，之后再混合在一起。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of great stuff here all about wines.
所以这里有很多关于葡萄酒的好内容。
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍这段对话。
Hello there.
你好。
Welcome to Wine World.
欢迎来到葡萄酒世界。
Let me know if I can help you out at all.
如果需要帮忙，请随时告诉我。
Yes, please.
好的，请。
I could really use some help.
我真的很需要一些帮助。
I'm going over to my boss's house for dinner tonight and I don't know what kind of wine
我今晚要去老板家吃晚饭，我不知道该带什么
I should bring.
酒。
Okay.
好的。
Do you know what kind of food will be served?
你知道会吃什么食物吗？
Well, his wife is Japanese.
嗯，他妻子是日本人。
He said she makes really good sushi.
他说她做的寿司很好吃。
That's a bit of a challenge.
这有点挑战性。
Sushi is notoriously difficult to pair with wine.
寿司是出了名的难与葡萄酒搭配。
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我想想。
It'll have to be a white wine, of course.
当然得是白葡萄酒。
Why wouldn't a red wine go well with sushi?
为什么红葡萄酒不能配寿司呢？
No, I don't think so.
不，我觉得不行。
Sushi is a very delicately flavored food and red wine would be a jarring contrast.
寿司是一种味道非常细腻的食物，红葡萄酒会形成刺眼的对比。
You need a white wine which has more subtle flavors to complement the fish.
你需要一种白葡萄酒，它有更微妙的风味来衬托鱼。
I see.
我明白了。
So I should get a bottle of Chardonnay.
所以我应该买一瓶霞多丽。
That's a white wine, right?
那是白葡萄酒，对吧？
Yes, Chardonnay is a white wine, but I'm not sure it'd be your best bet.
是的，霞多丽是白葡萄酒，但我不确定它是最好的选择。
Chardonnay is one of the more full-bodied whites and tends to be a bit oaky.
霞多丽是比较醇厚的白葡萄酒之一，而且往往带点橡木味。
I'd suggest you go for something brighter like this Sauvignon Blanc from New Zealand.
我建议你选一种更清爽的，比如这款新西兰的长相思。
Oh, the Sauvignon Blanc?
哦，长相思？
What's that?
那是什么？
That's another varietal or type of grape, just like Chardonnay.
那是另一种葡萄品种或类型，就像霞多丽一样。
Let's see.
让我看看。
The label says it's got attractive citrus and grassy aromas that give way to crisp mineral
标签上说它有诱人的柑橘和青草香气，带来清爽的矿物
flavors and a bone-dry finish.
风味和极干的口感。
Serve chilled.
冰镇后饮用。
Oh no, how long will it take to chill the wine?
哦不，冰镇这酒要多久？
I'm on my way to dinner now.
我现在就要去吃饭了。
Oh, it's okay.
哦，没关系。
Don't worry.
别担心。
We'll just choose a wine from the cooler.
我们直接从冷藏柜里选一瓶酒就行。
We don't have quite as extensive a selection over here, but this Rhone Valley White would
我们这边选择没那么丰富，但这瓶罗讷河谷白葡萄酒会
be lovely.
很不错。
All right, what varietal is that?
好的，那是什么葡萄品种？
Well, this is a French wine, so they don't always specify the varietal on the label.
嗯，这是法国酒，所以他们不总在标签上标明葡萄品种。
The French believe that the soil a grape is grown in is one of the most important factors
法国人认为葡萄生长的土壤是决定葡萄酒最终风味的最重要因素之一。
in the final flavor of the wine.
This wine is probably a blend of a few different types of grapes, mostly Viognier, I'd guess.
这瓶酒可能是几种不同葡萄的混酿，我猜主要是维欧尼。
And you think this is a good wine?
你觉得这是好酒吗？
Yes, this is one of our best sellers.
是的，这是我们最畅销的酒之一。
It's not quite as dry as the Sauvignon Blanc we were looking at earlier, which means it's
它不像我们之前看的那款长相思那么干，这意味着它
more approachable.
更容易入口。
It's light and crisp with a bit of a vanilla aroma.
它清淡爽口，带点香草香气。
Perfect.
完美。
I'll take it.
我就要这个了。
All right, so obviously there are a lot more varietals out there.
好的，显然还有很多其他葡萄品种。
We only talked about two types of wines.
我们只谈了两种酒。
We had a Chardonnay and a Sauvignon Blanc.
我们提到了霞多丽和长相思。
That's right.
没错。
And the only wines we talked about were white wines.
而且我们之前聊到的酒都是白葡萄酒。
Of course, there's a whole world of red wines out there.
当然，红葡萄酒的世界也很广阔。
And then between red and white, you have rosé, which are those pink wines.
在红葡萄酒和白葡萄酒之间，还有桃红葡萄酒，就是那些粉色的酒。
Those pink wines, yeah.
那些粉色的酒，是的。
But actually, it's interesting because the culture of drinking wine is not as extensive
但实际上，有趣的是，饮酒文化并没有我们想象的那么普及。
as we think it is.
在世界很多地方，人们并不习惯喝葡萄酒。
In many parts of the world, they're not really used to drinking wine.
没错。
That's right.
是的。
But then you go to places like France and Italy and South America, like Argentina, Chile,
但如果你去法国、意大利、南美，比如阿根廷、智利这些地方，
and you experience these different cultures of wine that are quite, I think, quite interesting
你会体验到不同的葡萄酒文化，我觉得这些文化相当有趣，
because they're so different.
因为它们差异很大。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
And it's become even healthy to drink wine.
而且喝葡萄酒甚至变得健康了。
Medical tests show that if you have one glass of wine with dinner every day, it reduces
医学研究表明，如果每天晚餐时喝一杯葡萄酒，可以降低
your chances of heart disease.
患心脏病的风险。
That's right.
没错。
There's some special ingredient.
里面含有某种特殊成分。
I'm not sure what it is, but obviously you don't want to drink too much.
我不确定具体是什么，但显然不能喝太多。
But if you have a little bit, it's good for your heart.
但如果适量饮用，对心脏有好处。
I think red wine, they say, is good for your heart.
据说红葡萄酒对心脏有好处。
So it's interesting, but obviously, maybe in your countries, you don't drink wine or
所以这很有趣，但显然，也许在你的国家，你们不喝葡萄酒，
maybe you have a particular type of wine.
或者你们有某种特定的酒。
Like in China, they have, isn't it plum wine or rice wine?
比如在中国，有梅酒或米酒，对吧？
Rice wine in China and plum wine, I think, in Japan.
中国有米酒，日本有梅酒，我想。
So maybe you have a specific type of wine that you want to let us know about.
所以也许你们有某种特定的酒想告诉我们。
And of course, if you have any questions or comments, we're always there.
当然，如果你们有任何问题或评论，我们随时都在。
Check us out at EnglishPod.com.
欢迎访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you again.
我们下次再见。
Thanks.
谢谢。